# MICHAEL SUGGS

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a software engineer who has spent the past year expanding my knowledge. Expertise in NodeJS with using ES6 syntax, and Python. I previously worked seven years in the medical field and am excited to make software development a career.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJS, Python, SQL, NodeJS

#### **PROJECTS**

## **SportDiscuss**

SportDiscuss created to discuss sports betting. Built with Python, JQuery, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.

#### Nextflick

Movie trailer app created with JQuery, HTML, and CSS. API calls to TMDB for up to date information.

## Michael's Pizzeria

Mock restaurant website for an Italian website. Created with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

### **EMPLOYMENT**

## Springboard Software Engineering Career Track

Student · Jan. 2021 to Current · Remote

700+ hours of education, hands-on coding challenges and assessments reviewed by industry expert. Weekly one on one work with industry expert mentor. and code reviews for all major projects. Building expertise in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

## Feeling Great Inc. - Sleep Medical Center

Registered Sleep Technologist · Apr. 2013 to Dec. 2020 · Jacksonville, NC

## **EDUCATION**

Lenoir Community CollegeAug. 2010 to May 2013